Jinyoung Kim

Data Scientist

www.jinyoung.kim me@jinyoung.kim 425-890-8269 Jinyoung (Jin) Kim is a data scientist, data enthusiast and data evangelist. In Microsoft, he has tackled challenging measurement problems in the area of web and conversational search. In his free time, he collects and analyzes various types of data on and around him.

He has published more than a dozen papers in the area of information retrieval and data mining, and recently published a book titled 'Hello, Data Science", which became a national bestseller (#1 in technology category) in Korea with critical acclaim.

He has taught tutorials in evaluation and measurement of online services in both Microsoft and SIGIR, and consulted various teams in Microsoft on metric and experiment design. He has also served in program committees and organized workshops in SIGIR, WSDM, WWW, ECIR conferences.

Experience

Microsoft Web Search and Al Science / Senior Applied Scientist

Aug 2012-Present

Research on measurement techniques for evaluating the search quality of Bing and other search products. Specialize in improving the quality of editorial judgments, designing metrics and experiments.

Microsoft Research / Research Intern

Jun 2011 - Aug 2011

Developed a user profiling method based on the combination of reading level and topic. Explored applications of the method for personalized search and expert content classification.

T&C Technology / Software Engineer

Jan 2003 - Jan 2006

Designed and developed a billing system for large telephone companies in Korea which can handle millions of transactions a day.

Education

University of Massachusetts at Amherst / Ph.D. in Computer Science

Ph.D Dissertation: Retrieval and evaluation techniques for personal information

Seoul National University / B.S. in Electrical Engineering

1999-2007

Graduated with Cum Laude

Selected Publications

Hello. Data Science

Jinyoung Kim, Published by Hanbit Media, 2016.

(full list here)

Explicit In Situ User Feedback for Web Search Results

Jin Young Kim, Jaime Teevan and Nick Craswell. 2016. In Proceedings of the 39th Annual International ACM SIGIR (SIGIR).

Toward Predicting the Outcome of an A/B Experiment for Search Relevance

Lihong Li, Jin Young Kim, and Imed Zitouni. 2015. In Proceedings of the Eighth ACM International Conference on Web Search and Data Mining (WSDM).

Contextual and dimensional relevance judgments for reusable SERP-level evaluation

Peter B. Golbus, Imed Zitouni, Jin Young Kim, Ahmed Hassan, and Fernando Diaz. 2014. In Proceedings of the 23rd international conference on World wide web (WWW).

Understanding Web Search Interactions with Dynamic Results Generated using Implicit Feedback

Jin Young Kim, Mark Cramer, Jaime Teevan, Dmitry Lagun. 2013. In Proceedings of the 22nd ACM Conference on Information and Knowledge Management (CIKM).

Relevance Dimensions in Preference-Based IR Evaluation

Jin Young Kim, Gabriella Kazai, Imed Zitouni. 2013. In Proceedings the 35th annual international ACM SIGIR Conference on Research and Development in Information Retrieval (SIGIR).

Characterizing web content, user interests, and search behavior by reading level and topic

Jin Young Kim, Kevyn Collins-Thompson, Paul N. Bennett, Susan T. Dumais. 2012. In Proceedings of 5th ACM International Conference on Web Search and Data Mining, Seattle, WA, USA (WSDM).

A Field Relevance Model for Structured Document Retrieval

Jin Young Kim and W. Bruce Croft. 2012. In Proceedings of the 34th European Conference on Information Retrieval (ECIR), Barcelona, Spain.

Patents

$Improving\ Judgment\ Quality\ in\ Side-by-side\ Evaluation$

8/28/2015

Task-level Search Engine Evaluation

8/11/2015

Offline Evaluation of Ranking Functions

11/21/2014

Behavior-based Evaluation of Crowd Worker Quality

6/5/2014

Invited Talks / Tutorial

IR Evaluation: Designing an End-to-End Offline Evaluation Pipeline

Half-day Tutorial in SIGIR'15, Aug 8, 2015.

Data Science in Industry

Department of Mathematics, University of Washington, Jun 4, 2015.